Ivan Fanello

Frontend Engineer/ Ux Designer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivan-fanello-25b344230 https://github.com/wisepanda



My journey in tech started in 2008 with my first job in a mobile shop retailer. There I was able to use the first touch screens before they became affordable and well known by everyone. I have always had a passion for tech since my first home computer but the experience I had there working with cutting edge technology is something I wanted to experience again. After, life has taken me on a different journey and I have had a great time growing in the hospitality industry, but during the pandemic I felt I wanted to improve my life and career further, so I applied to School of Code and took on the challenge of changing my life.

Working as a manager in the hospitality industry for the last six years, I have developed skills I feel confident can add value to any team, and the bootcamp has given me new knowledge and interests I want to develop further. During my career, I have learned that good communication, respect and understanding are the fundamentals of every successful team. I enjoy a challenge and love leading a team to success.

If I had to describe myself in a few words, I would say that I am creative, responsible and always open to dialogue.

Soft skills:

- Creativity
- Communication
- Leadership
- Problem solving
- Team training
- Team organization
- Team management
- Reliability
- **Critical Thinking**
- **Human Resources**

Tech Skills:























WORK EXPERIENCE

School of Code / Bootcamper

November 2021 - March 2022

School of code is an intensive bootcamp that covers the most modern and commonly used technologies in software development (see tech skills above), with a strong focus on pair programming. Below is a breakdown of some core principles and skills developed during the bootcamp:

- Computational thinking: the ability to deconstruct a problem and solve it in smaller fragments is a precious skill I now apply in everyday life, not just in coding.
- Pair programming: I have always enjoyed working in teams and consider myself a good colleague to engage with, but working in new groups every week with people that have different kinds of experience has definitely been a challenge. I have learnt the importance of making everyone feel at ease, being more confident in my skills and maintaining my focus under pressure.
- Learning: the intensive structure of the bootcamp really puts you under pressure and improving your way of understanding and learning is fundamental. Many times we had to research new programming languages alone and create apps using them. I can say that reading docs is not that scary anymore.
- > Projects and hackathons: Every step of the way we have been challenged with different tasks, problems to solve and apps to develop. Trusting your team, delegating and having an MVP are fundamentals to succeed.
- Agile: I understand and appreciate the benefits of agile methodologies. I think that having daily stand ups, iterative sprints and retros is a healthy and successful way of running a business and managing teams.

No11 Pimlico Road / Manager

August 2019 - November 2021, Darwin and Wallace, London

At No11 Pimlico Road, venue of the Darwin & Wallace group, I was part of a small management team and worked at close contact with our general manager, dealing with a wide spectrum of responsibilities. My main duties were:

- > HR (contracts, documents check, recruitment, staff training)
- ➤ Health and safety procedures
- > Shift management, customers satisfaction and complaints
- ➤ Team allocation
- > Events management and organization
- > Security and cash reconciliation
- > Stocktake, ordering and budget management

Crofton Park Tavern Tavern / Assistant General Manager

February 2019 - July 2019, London

Hired as AGM for the opening of a new venue I was responsible with the General Manager of all the practices and set ups from day one. My responsibilities:

- ➤ Health & safety procedures
- ➤ Human resources (contracts, staff files, recruitment and rotas)
- Cocktail and food menu creation
- > Setting up tills systems and stock management softwares (Access, Fourth)
- GP and pricelist calculations
- > Bar, restaurant and cellar organization
- > Shift management and customers complaints
- Staff training
- > Stock taking, ordering and budget management

L.T. Cocktail & Wine Bar / Manager

October 2018 - February 2019, London

L.T Cocktail & Wine bar was a modern Italian bar, serving pizzas and sharing plates as well as wines, cocktails and spirits. As the only manager of a small business I was in charge of both running the venue and managing the back of house daily. During my short time there I was able to:

- Change the whole wine and cocktail list reducing costs and achieving a more accessible pricing
- > Increase the affluence to the bar, introducing a two for one on bespoke and classic cocktails on a happy hour offer
- Increased the cash flow and sales of the venue
- Organize full venue hires through advertisement on social medias and mailing lists
- Partially refurbish the venue
- ➤ Hire new team members
- Reduce costs managing stock better

EDUCATION

Marco Polo Tourism High School / Diploma

September 2003 - August 2008, Florence, Italy

Subjects:

Languages: English, French, Spanish

Literature, History, Math, geography Business Economy, travel planning, Arts